Finding Aid for the Delbert Mann Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- December 2008
  - Videocassettes
    - OTHELLO (Box 1)
    - OUR TOWN, 1955 (Box 1)
    - THE OUTSIDER, 1960 (Box 1)
    - PETRIFIED FOREST, MAY 1955 (Box 1)
    - PLOT TO KILL STALIN – PLAYHOUSE 90 (Box 1)
    - RABBIT TRAP –PHILCO- GOODYEAR PLAYHOUSE, 1955 (Box 1)
    - RED MILL – Dupont Show ofthe Month (Box 1)
    - SATURDAYNIGHTATTHE MOVIES, 1995 (Box 1)
    - SEARCH (Box 1)
    - SEPARATE TABLES (Box 1)
    - SOMEBODY SPECIAL, 1954 (Box 1)
    - SENSE AND SENSIBILITY GOODYEAR TELEVISION PLAYHOUSE, 1950 (Box 1)
    - STAGE 10 LIVE: A CELEBRATION OF THE GOLDEN AGE OF TELEVISION, 1988 (Box 1)
    - STAGE 10 LIVE: A CELEBRATION OF THE GOLDEN AGE OF TELEVISION (THE PETRIFIED FOREST) (Box 1)
    - SUITABLE FOR FRAMING (Box 1)
    - THE SYMBOL (Box 1)
    - TORCH FOR A DARK JOURNEY –PHILCO TV PLAYHOUSE, 1950 (Box 1)
    - TRADE SECRETS (Box 1)
    - THE DARK AT THE TOP OF THE STAIRS (Box 1)
    - WISH ON THE MOON – GOODYEAR TV PLAYHOUSE, 1953 (Box 1)
    - WITHOUT FEAR OR FAVOR (Box 1)
    - YELLOW JACK – PRODUCERS’ SHOWCASE (Box 1)
    - ACADEMY AWARDS – RUSSIA- ARGENTINA-NOME, 1987 (Box 2)
    - APRIL MORNING, 1987 (Box 2)
    - BEST LAID PLANS, 1952 (Box 2)
    - BIRCH INTERVAL, 1975 (Box 2)
    - DAVID COPPERFIELD (Box 2)
    - DAY LINCOLN WAS SHOT, 1956 (Box 2)
    - DEAR HEART, 1963 (Box 2)
    - A DEATH IN CALIFORNIA, 1985 (Box 2)
    - DELBERT MANN INTERVIEW; TODAY SHOW- ALL THE WAY HOME; ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT; PM MAGAZINE: KENNEDY CHALLENGE; IN SEARCH OF TOWER OF LONDON MURDERS (Box 2)
    - DEL MANN TRIBUTE – TURNER CLASSIC MOVIES 11-30-00 (Box 2)
    - DARK AT THE TOP OF THE STAIRS; SEPARATE TABLES; DEAR HEART; MR. BUDDWING (Box 2)
    - ERNIE BARGER IS 50- PH/LCD TV PLAYHOUSE, 1953 (Box 2)
    - FIRST WOMAN PRESIDENT, 1974 (Box 2)
    - F/TZWILLY, 1967 (Box 2)
    - GATHERING OF EAGLES, 1962 (Box 2)
    - THE GIFT OF LOVE, 1983 (Box 2)
    - GIGGI MAKES A CHESS PIE, 1989 (Box 2)
    - A GIRL NAMED SOONER, 1974 (Box 2)
    - HOME TO STAY, 2001 (Box 2)
    - THE HUNTRESS, 1954 (Box 2)
    - INCIDENT IN BALTIMORE, 1991 (Box 2)
    - INTIMATE PORTRAITS: GRACE KELLY, 1980 (Box 2)
    - I WAS STALIN’S PRISONER – GOODYEAR TV PLAYHOUSE, 1951 (Box 2)
    - KIDNAPPED – 1999 (2 TAPES) (Box 2)
    - THE LEGENDARY CURSE OF THE HOPE DIAMOND, 1975 (Box 2)
    - LOVE LEADS THE WAY, 1990 (Box 2)
    - LOVE’S DARK RIDE, 1977 (Box 2)
    - MEMBER OF THE WEDDING, 1990 (Box 2)
    - MEMOIRS OF ABRAHAM LINCOLN, 1991 (Box 2)
    - MEMOIRS OF ABRAHAM LINCOLN, 1993 (Box 2)
    - MISTER BUDDWING, 1965 (Box 2)
    - OCTOBER STORY (Box 2)
    - THE COPPER -GOODYEAR T.V. PLAYHOUSE, 1981 (Box 2)
    - THE PINK JUNGLE, 1967 (Box 2)
    - QUICK BEFORE IT MELTS, 1964 (Box 2)
    - THE RECLUSE, 1953 (Box 2)
    - RITA, 2003 (Box 2)
    - SATURDAY ADOPTION, 1992 (Box 2)
    - SHE WAITS – 1971 (AIR COPY) (Box 2)
    - TELL ME MY NAME, 1977 (Box 2)
    - TELL ME MY NAME, 1995 (Box 2)
    - TO FIND MY SON, 1980 (Box 2)
    - TOM AND JOANNE, 1978 (Box 2)
    - TRIBUTE TO FRED COE (Box 2)
    - WHAT MAKES SAMMY RUN? (EDITED VERSION) – MUSEUM OF TELEVISION AND RADIO (Box 2)
    - ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT (3 TAPES) (Box 3)
    - BRONTE – 1983 REEL 1 (Box 3)
    - BRONTE – 1983 REEL 2 (Box 3)
    - DELBERT MANN INTERVIEW, MAY 20, 1997 – 9 TAPES (Box 3)
    - DELBERT MANN Q&A (Box 3)
    - DELBERT MANN RETROSPECTIVE (Box 3)
    - FRANK CAPRA MEMORIAL SERVICE (Box 3)
    - GRACE KELLY: THE AMERICAN PRINCESS (Box 3)
    - HEIDI (Box 3)
    - JANE EYRE (PART 1) (Box 3)
    - JANE EYRE (PART 2) (Box 3)
    - THE LAST DAYS OF PATTON, 1985 (Box 3)
    - MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT: A CONVERSATION WITH DELBERT MANN AND EVA MARIE SAINT (Box 3)
    - NFL DISTANT REPLAY 2002 WEEK 13 “HEIDI GAME’ (Box 3)
    - PLOT TO KILL STALIN – PLAYHOUSE 90 – 1991 (2 TAPES) (Box 3)
    - SEPARATE TABLES (Box 3)
    - SEPARATE TABLES (Box 3)
    - THE TED KENNEDY, JR. STORY, 1986 (Box 3)
    - THAT TOUCH OF MINK, 1992 (Box 3)
    - THOU SHALT NOT COMMIT ADULTERY, 1981 (Box 3)
    - THE TUNNEL – PLAYHOUSE 90- 1991 (2 TAPES) (Box 3)
    - ANGELA LANSBURY: A BALANCING ACT, 1998 (Box 4)
    - ANN MANN’S APPEARANCE IN R.R.STATION SCENE – “INCIDENT” (Box 4)
    - APRIL MORNING, 1983 (Box 4)
    - BIRTH OF THE MOVIES – PHILCO TELEVISION PLAYHOUSE, 1951 (Box 4)
    - DARKNESS AT NOON – PRODUCERS SHOWCASE, 1955 (Box 4)
    - DELBERT MANN ARCHIVAL PROJECT (Box 4)
    - DELBERT MANN SATURDAY NIGHT AT THE MOVIES, FEBRUARY 25, 1995 (Box 4)
    - HOLLYWOOD GREATS – DAVID NIVEN (Box 4)
    - IRONCLADS, 1991 (Box 4)
    - IRONCLADS: BEHIND THE SCENES, 1991 (Box 4)
    - JUBILEE: THE STORY OF HOW THE FISK JUBILEE SINGERS INTRODUCED THE NEGRO SPIRITUAL TO THE WORLD, SEPTEMBER 15, 1997 (Box 4)
    - LOVER COME BACK, 1961 (Box 4)
    - MAN WITHOUT A COUNTRY, 1972 (Box 4)
    - A MAN WITHOUT A COUNTRY, 1991 (Box 4)
    - MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT, 1959 (Box 4)
    - THE RICH BOY – 1952- PHILCO PLAYHOUSE (Box 4)
    - SEGMENT, 1952 (Box 4)
  - Large Videocassette Tapes
    - ERNIE BARGER IS FIFTY ( 1 videocassette—black and white, 59:38, 8-9-53, Philco Television Playhouse ) (Box 1)
    - INCIDENT IN A SMALL TOWN (2 videocassettes –Rill Entertainment version) (Box 1)
    - LAST DAYS OF PATTON (Part I –reels 1 and 2, Part II—reels 3 and 4, Part III—reel 5) (Box 1)
    - THE MEMOIRS OF ABRAHAM LINCOLN ( 2 Videos—Wisconsin Public Television) (Box 1)
    - SONNY VANDUSEN INTERVIEW—THE MEMOIRS OF ABRAHAM LINCOLN (1 video) (Box 1)
    - SANTA CLARIJA FILM FESTIVAL—BOB TAYLOR’S BACKYARD (Box 1)
    - THE TEDDY KENNEDY STORY (Parts I and II –2 videos 35mm print) (Box 1)
    - THOU SHALT NOT COMMIT ADULTERY (Parts I and II—2 videos—Edgar J. Scherick Productions (Box 1)
    - TOM AND JOANNE ( 1 videocassette—51 minutes ) (Box 1)
    - TORN BETWEEN TWO LOVERS (Parts I and II –2 videos Alan Landsburg Productions, 1554 S. Sepulveda Blvd. LA 90025 ) (Box 1)
  - Videocassettes
    - April Morning—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 2)
    - Bachelor Party—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 2)
    - Birch Interval—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 2)
    - David Copperfield 1 tape (Box 2)
    - Desire Under the Elm—1 tape (Box 2)
    - Middle of the Night— Parts 1 and 2 (Box 2)
    - The Outsider – Parts 1 and 2 (Box 2)
    - The Plot to Kill Stalin—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 2)
    - Santa Clarija Film Festiveal (Box 2)
    - The Tunnel—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 2)
    - Breaking Up—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 3)
    - Death in California—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 3)
    - A Gathering of Eagles—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 3)
    - A Girl Named Sooner—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 3)
    - Jane Eyre—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 3)
    - Kidnapped – Parts 1 and 2 (Box 3)
    - The Recluse—1 tape (Box 3)
    - Tell Me My Name – Parts 1 and 2 (Box 3)
    - Dark at the Top of the Stairs—Parts 1, 2, and 3 (Box 4)
    - Darkness at Noon –Parts 1, 2, and 3 (Box 4)
    - Ford Star Jubilee: The Day Lincoln was Shot (1956) Parts 1 and 2 (Box 4)
    - Love’s Dark Ride—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 4)
    - Man Without a Country—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 4)
    - The Medea Cup— 1 tape (Box 4)
    - Separate Tables – Parts 1 and 2 (Box 4)
    - David Copperfield—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 5)
    - Dear Heart—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 5)
    - The Dupont Show of the Month: The Red Mill—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 5)
    - Heidi—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 5)
    - Lover Come Back—Parts 1, 2, and 3 (Box 5)
    - That Touch of Mink—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 5)
    - That Touch of Mink—Parts 1 and 2 (Box 5)
    - To Find My Son –parts 1 and 2 (Box 6)
    - How to Stay—parts 1 and 2 (Box 6)
    - Mr. Buddwing—parts 1 and 2 (Box 6)
    - The Legendary Curse of the Hope Diamond—1 videocassette (Box 6)
    - Ben Franklin—1 videocassette (Box 6)
    - The First Woman President (Box 6)
    - The Harvard Show—parts 1 and 2 (Box 6)
    - Marty—parts 1 and 2 (Box 6)
    - All Quiet on the Western Front—parts 1, 2, and 3 (Box 7)
    - Bronte—parts 1 and 2 (Box 7)
    - Francis Gary Powers—parts 1 and 2 (Box 7)
    - The Gift of Love—parts 1 and 2 (Box 7)
    - Quick Before It Melts—parts 1 and 2 (Box 7)
    - CBS Playhouse—Saturday Adoption–parts 1 and 2 (Box 7)
    - All the Way Home—parts 1 and 2 (Box 8)
    - Death in California—parts 1 and 2 (Box 8)
    - Fitzwilly—parts 1 and 2 (Box 8)
    - Night Crossing—parts 1 and 2 (Box 8)
    - Our Town—parts 1 and 2 (Box 8)
    - Yellow Jack—parts 1 and 2 (Box 8)
    - ¾” Video tapes (Box 9)
    - Air date
      - Operation Airlift (Philco Playhouse), 6-17-1951 (Box 9)
      - Without Fear or Favor (Goodyear Playhouse), 1-13-52 (Box 9)
      - The Rich Boy, 2-10-52 (Box 9)
      - The Best Laid Schemes, 3-23-53 (Box 9)
      - Search, 12-7-52 (Box 9)
      - Double Jeopardy (Philco), 1-4-53 (Box 9)
      - Wish on the Moon (Goodyear), 3-29-53 (Box 9)
      - Marty, 5-24-53 (Box 9)
      - Marty (on the Golden Age of Televison series), 5-24-53 (Box 9)
      - Ernie Barger is Fifty, 8-9-53 (Box 9)
      - Middle of the Night, 9-19-54 (Box 9)
  - Videocassettes ¾”
    - Against Her Will Reels 1 and 2 (95 min.), (9/10/91) (Box 10)
    - April Morning Parts I (42:41) and II (56:40), (10/20/87) (Box 10)
    - April Morning Parts I (42:41) and II(56:40), (10/20/87) (Box 10)
  - Videocassettes ½”
    - April Morning (Box 10)
    - Bronte –Reels 1 and 2, (1982) (Box 10)
    - The Gift of Love, (1983) (Box 10)
    - A Girl Named Sooner (Box 10)
    - Hollywood Remembers The Blacklist Line Cut# 1 and# 2 (Box 10)
    - Hollywood Remembers the Blacklist 10/27/97 (not for air) (Box 10)
    - Incident in a Small Town (12/2/ 93) Final corrected (Box 10)
    - Incident in a Small Town (12/14/1993) air copy, revised sound (Box 10)
    - Intimate Portraits: Grace Kelly (off the air ) (Box 10)
    - Ironclads—Monitor vs. Merrimack (Box 10)
    - Kidnapped—Reels 1 and 2, (1971) (Box 10)
    - Kidnapped—Reels 1 and 2 tied (99min.) (1971)—2 copies (Box 10)
    - Lily in Winter (94:37) (Box 10)
    - Lily in Winter –Electronic Press Kit (Box 10)
    - Night Crossing (Box 10)
    - Separate Tables (99:22), 1957-58 (Box 10)
    - Marty –Part 1 of 1 (90 min.) TV, 5/24/53 (Box 10)
    - The Ted Kennedy Jr. Story (1 hour, 32 min.) (work print not color corrected) (Box 10)
    - Ted Kennedy Jr. (c. 1986) Craig Nelson, Susan Blakley (Box 10)
    - To Find My Son (Box 10)
  - Videocassettes ¾”
    - All Quiet on the Western Front: Promo (Box 11)
    - Delbert Mann Interview (Dub) Aired 2/28/81 Length 16:03 (Box 11)
    - God’s Guerillas (30:00 mins.), 8-12-81 (Box 11)
    - In Search of ... The Tower of London Murders (21:30 mins.) (Box 11)
    - Ironclads Parts I( 56:55) and 2(36:46) (1-14-91) (Box 11)
    - Love Leads the Way Parts I (60:38) and 2( 41:17), 8/23/84 (Box 11)
    - Making It Special: The Filming of “A Girl Named Sooner” (43:30 mins.) This rough cut was edited in, November 1974 (Box 11)
    - Member of the Wedding Acts 1, 2, and 3 (3 reels), (12/20/ 82) (Box 11)
    - Othello, (August 27, 1950) (Box 11)
    - PM Magazine “Kennedy Challenge” (5:43) (Box 11)
    - Today Show: All the Way Home, (Dec. 21, 1981) (Box 11)
    - Dear Heart c. 1963, G. Ford, G. Page (Box 12)
    - The Huntress 2/14/54 Goodyear Television Playhouse (Box 12)
    - Jane Eyre Summer, 1970 (Box 12)
    - A Man Without a Country Part 1 of 2 (53:15), 1/30/87 (Box 12)
    - The Marriages, Jan. 22, 1950 (Box 12)
  - Videocassettes ½”
    - “Marty” Instant Recall ABC 11/19/90 (TV Version), 5/24/53 (Box 12)
    - Memoirs of Abraham Lincoln (dubbed 1/26/93) video OK, sound not (Box 12)
    - Memoirs of Abraham Lincoln 1/14/93 Complete Show Video OK, Sound not (Box 12)
    - Middle of the Night (59: 33) 9/19/54 Philco Television Playhouse (Box 12)
    - Pink Jungle Air Copy Damaged (Box 12)
    - Segment, Jan. 27, 1952 (Box 12)
    - The Symbol, Jan. 5, 1951 (Box 12)